Guide to the Elinor Miller Papers 1977-2004 MSS 178 MSS 178
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series II: Correspondence, Miller to Butor and others
  - Correspondence from Elinor Miller - Fragments, undated (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - Elinor Miller's personal file entitled "To send Butor", undated (Box 2, Folder 94)
- Series III: Mixed Media/Collaborations
  This series is comprised of mixed media depicting the work of several artists with whom Butor collaborated. Miller's labeling titles have been retained. Miller wrote on these artists and their collaborations with Butor, and taught classes on them as well. There are slides, photos, photo CDs, and audiocassettes. There is also a VHS of a Butor interview. Access copies may not yet be available for these materials. Please check with a Fales Archivist.
  - Slides: 3 Suisses, undated (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Slides: Alechinsky Traité des modernes(Balzac), undated (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Slides: Alechinsky duplicates/ Kolar Autopart, undated (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - Slides: Masurovsky Pont de la machine/ Alechinsky, undated (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Slides: Bougie Entre Deux Eaux (de chance), undated (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - Slides: 3 Suisses, undated (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - Slides: Most of Michel Butor et ses peintres, most in duplicate, undated (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - Slides: Alechinsky [see slide box], undated (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - Slides: BK, undated (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - Slides: Canadians, undated (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Slides: Elinor Miller - used by Rollins paper, undated (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - Slides: Kolar, undated (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - Slides: Badin Jardin Catalan, undated (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - Slides: Memory, undated (Box 3, Folder 108)
  - Slides: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - Slides: Kolar, undated (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - Slides: Alechinsky - December 8, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 111)
  - One Kolar print, undated (Box 3, Folder 112)
  - Kolar prints and negatives, undated (Box 3, Folder 113)
  - Slides and list: 3 Suisses, undated (Box 3, Folder 114)
  - Two photo CDs of 3 Suisses, undated (Box 3, Folder 115)
  - Videocassette: Michel Butor, Petite histoire de la littérature française: Entretiens avec Lucien Giraudo, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 116)
  - Audiocassette: Butor NYU, Oct '94, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 117)
- Series IV: Printed Material
  The printed material included in the collection consists of secondary works and catalogs. The secondary sources are arranged alphabetically by author, the catalogs alphabetically by title.
  - Subseries A: Secondary Works
    - Book-Senninger, Claude and Jack Kolbert, Eds. L'Art de Michel Butor. New York: Oxford University Press, 1970. (Box 4, Folder 118)
    - "Butor." L'Arc: Revue trimestrielle. ( 39) 1969. (Box 4, Folder 119)
    - Calle-Gruber, Mireille, Ed. Butor et L'Amerique. L'Harmattan, 1998. (Box 4, Folder 120)
    - Calle-Gruber, Mireille and Clive Thompson, Eds. Butor Pluriel. Kingston, Ontario: Département d'Études Françaises, Queen's University, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 121)
    - Calle-Gruber, Mireille. La Ville dans L'Emploi du temps de Michel Butor. Paris: Librairie A.-G. Nizet, 1995. (Box 4, Folder 122)
    - Calle-Gruber, Mireille. Les Métamorphoses Butor: Entretiens de Mireille Calle. Québec: Éditions Griffon d'argile, 1997. (Box 4, Folder 123)
    - Calle-Gruber, Mireille. "Portrait de l'artiste en Dieu Thot." New Novel Review, 1:2 17-31, April 1994. (Box 4, Folder 124)
    - Calle-Gruber, Mireille. "Quant à l'oeuvre Butor: Entretiens avec Michel Butor, Jean Starobinski et Jean-Francois Lyotard." Revue des Sciences Humanies 221, 1991. (Box 4, Folder 125)
    - Camarero, Jesús. Bibliographica Butoriana. Vitoria: ARTeragin, 1996. (Box 4, Folder 126)
    - Camarero, Jesús. "Recherces formelles: Michel Butor et la mobilité." Studies in Comparative Literature 17., undated (Box 4, Folder 127)
    - Charbonnier, Georges. Entretiens avec Michel Butor. Gallimard, 1967. (Box 4, Folder 128)
    - Dällenbach, Lucien. Butor aux quatre vents. Paris: José Corti, 1997. (Box 4, Folder 129)
    - Helbo, André. Michel Butor: vers une littérature du signe. Bruxelles: Éditions Complexe, 1975. (Box 4, Folder 130)
    - La Mothe, Jacques. Butor en perspective. L'Harmattan, 2002. (Box 4, Folder 131)
    - La Mothe, Jacques. L'Architexture du rêve: la littérature et les arts dans Matière de rêves de Michel Butor. Amsterdam: Rodopi, 1999. (Box 4, Folder 132)
    - Le Sidaner, Jean-Marie. Michel Butor: Voyageur a la roue. Paris: Encre Éditions, 1979. (Box 4, Folder 133)
    - Lester, Cheryl. "Signifying at the Frontier." Kansas English, 80:2, 10-15, 1993. (Box 4, Folder 134)
    - Lydon, Mary. Perpetuum Mobile: A Study of the Novels and Aesthetics of Michel Butor. Alberta, Alberta University Press, 1980. (Box 4, Folder 135)
    - McWilliams, Dean. The Narratives of Michel Butor: The Writer as Janus. Ohio University Press, 1978. (Box 4, Folder 136)
    - Mécif, Yvan. Remanances 6, 1996. (Box 4, Folder 137)
    - Miller, Elinor. "Approaches to the Cataract: Butor's Niagara." Studies in Twentieth Century Literature, 2:1, 33-35, 1977. (Box 4, Folder 138)
    - Miller, Elinor. "Butor's Beautiful Decay." Romance Notes 29:1, 61-71, 1988. (Box 4, Folder 139)
    - Miller, Elinor. "Butor's Quadruple Fond as Serial Music." Romance Notes 24:2, 1984. (Box 4, Folder 140)
    - Miller, Elinor. "Introduction to Butor et ses peintres." Yearbook of Comparative and General Literature 38, 39-72, 1989. [Two Copies] (Box 4, Folder 141)
    - Perros, Georges. Lettres à Michel Butor. Éditions Ubacs, 1979. [Two Volumes], 1982 (Box 4, Folder 142)
    - Peyré, Yves. Peinture et poesie: le dialogue par le livre. Gallimard, 2002. (Box 5, Folder 143)
    - Raillard, Georges, Ed. Colloque de Cerisy. Paris: Union générale d'éditions, 1974. (Box 5, Folder 144)
    - Rogers, Michelle. "Interview avec Michel Butor." The French Review 54:4, 509-517, 1984. (Box 5, Folder 145)
    - Roudiez, Leon S. "Michel Butor." French Fiction Revisited. Elmwood Park: Dalkey Archive Press, 1991. (Box 5, Folder 146)
    - Santschi, Madeline. Voyage avec Michel Butor. Lausanne: L'Age d'Homme, 1982. (Box 5, Folder 147)
    - Sicard, Michel, Ed. Christian Dotremont, Michel Butor: Cartes et Lettres. Paris: Galilée, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 148)
    - Sullivan, Francoise Dupuy. "Qui parle dans Degrès?" The French Review 64:6, 956-966, 1991. (Box 5, Folder 149)
    - Teulon-Nouailles, Skimao and Bernard Teulon-Nouailles. Michel Butor qui êtes-vous? Lyon: La manufacture, 1988. (Box 5, Folder 150)
    - University of Oklahoma. "Michel Butor Conference." November 1981. [Program] (Box 5, Folder 151)
    - University of Oklahoma. World Literature Today: The Michel Butor Issue, 56:2, 1982. (Box 5, Folder 152)
    - Van Rossum-Guyon, Francoise. Le Coeur critique: Butor, Simon, Kristeva, Cixous. Amsterdam and Atlanta, GA: Rodopi, 1997. (Box 5, Folder 153)
    - Waelti-Walters, Jennifer. Michel Butor. Amsterdam and Atlanta, GA: Rodopi,1992. (Box 5, Folder 154)
    - Walters, Jennifer. "Butor's Use of Literary Texts in Degrès." PMLA 88:2, 311-321, 1973. (Box 5, Folder 155)
  - Subseries B: Catalogs
    - 13 Artistes avec Michel Butor. Chapelle de la Visitation, salle de l'Academie Chablaisienne: Galerie Art/Espace, 1997. (Box 5, Folder 156)
    - 22 Artistes avec Michel Butor. Médiatheque Louis Aragon, 1998. (Box 5, Folder 157)
    - Apesanteur. Marc Jurt, Michel Butor. [Two Copies], undated (Box 5, Folder 158)
    - Art and the New Novel: Parallels and Generators. Falck Gallery, 1994. (Box 5, Folder 159)
    - Artistes avec Michel Butor/ Butor mit Künstlern. Zürich: Collegium Helveticum, 1997. (Box 5, Folder 160)
    - Cent Livres du Michel Butor. Laon: Musée de Laon, 1990. (Box 5, Folder 161)
    - Clarbous. Centre de Développement Culturel de Foix et de l'Ariège, 1991. (Box 5, Folder 162)
    - Le Congrès des cuillers. Génève: Musée Barbier-Mueller, 1986. (Box 5, Folder 163)
    - Constellation Michel Butor. Université de Génève, 1989. (Box 5, Folder 164)
    - Georges Badin-Michel Butor. Galerie Berthet-Aittouarés, 2000. (Box 5, Folder 165)
    - Le Jardin Catalan. Ecoblade., undated (Box 5, Folder 166)
    - Julius Balthazar. Art Gallery, 1990. (Box 5, Folder 167)
    - J.C. Prêtre. London: Brompton Gallery, 1985. (Box 5, Folder 168)
    - Michel Butor et ses peintres. Musée des Beaux-Arts du Havre, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 169)
    - Oeuvres croisées fourmillement. Montpelier: Galerie Matisse, 1990. (Box 5, Folder 170)
    - Passage de Butor II. Montpelier: Galerie Wimmer;Bédarieux: Musée de Bédarieux, 1991. (Box 5, Folder 171)
    - Pi ou le cercle des roues. Galerie Phillipe Boutibonnes, 1990. (Box 5, Folder 172)
    - Seize et une variations d'Albert Ayme. Paris: Edition Traversiere, 1983. (Box 5, Folder 173)
    - Texturas no. 2. Vittoria: 1991-92. (Box 5, Folder 174)
    - Vieira da Silva. Lisbon: Pagine d'Arte, 1997. (Box 5, Folder 175)
    - William J. Jones Collections: Rimbaud-Butor at Southwest Missouri State University. St. Aubyn, F.C. Springfield, Missouri: The Friends of the SMSU Libraries, 1986. [Two Copies] (Box 5, Folder 176)
- OVERSIZE Series IV: Printed Material
  The oversize objects for Series IV consist of museum catalogs arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Subseries B: Museum Catalogs
    - 7 and 6. New Mexico: Hoshour Gallery, 1988. (Box 6, Folder 177)
    - D'Après Suzanne. Prêtre, J.C. Génève: Galerie Andata/Ritorno, 1993. (Box 6, Folder 178)
    - Suzanne. Prêtre, J.C. Paris: La Bibliotheque des Arts, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 179)
    - Un Jour nous construirons les pyramides. Musée Barbier Mueller, 1990. (Box 6, Folder 180)